umbar General Insurance company
limited's for FY 2024 and fy2 24
earnings conference
call from the Senior Management we have
with us today Mr sanjie mantri MD and
CEO of the company Mr gopal balachandran
CFO Mr alok Agarwal executive
director Mr Girish nyak Chief technology
and health underwriting and claims Mr s
gadia Chief corporate solutions group
and Mr annand singi Chief retail and
government
business please note that any statements
or comments made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as the future involves risks
and uncertainties which could cause
results to differ materially from the
current Ms being
expressed as a reminder all participant
lines will be in the listen only mode
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during this conference please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your touchone
phone I now hand the conference over to
Mr sanjie mantri MD and CEO ICICI lombar
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over to you sir thank
you good evening to each one of you
thank you for joining the earning
conference call of icsa lombar limited
for quarter 4 and financial year
2024 let me give you a brief overview of
the industry Trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the past few
months po this our CFO Mr goal Balan
will share the financial performance of
the company for the course and the year
ended March 31st
2024 during the quarter ban economy
continued its robust growth trajectory
with key high frequency indicators
reflecting healthy economic conditions
for the financial year 2024 India's GDP
growth is expected to be
7.6% looking ahead a normal Southwest
Monsoon should support agriculture
activity boost rural demand and help
overall
sentiments however any worst thing of
geopolitical tension or a global
slowdown may have an adverse
impact now talking about Auto industry
Private Car Sales witness Rob robust
growth for the financial year 2024 aided
by improved supplies and sustained
customer demand as per CM data over 4.2
million Vehicles were sold in the year
the industry also saw saw a shift in the
customer preference from entry-level
cars to SUV thus contribution of SUV in
private car segment has gone up from 37%
to 49% in last 2
years as mentioned in the earn last
earning calls upti in rural demand saw
two wheer sales grow by
25% in Q4 to touch 4.5 million the
annual two- wheer sales also surpassed
the financial year 2020 figure and stood
at 18 million Vehicles during the year
around 1.7 million commercial VRE were
sold which was D driven primarily by
good Traction in infra and other core
sectors health insurance contined to be
the largest product segment for the
industry as for data published in the I
annual report for financial year 2023
the growth in number of lives have been
primly given by the group health
business and we expect this trend to
continue for financial year 2024 as
well the commercial line of business
witness growth supported by strong
government capital expenditure related
to infrastructure development
consequently engineering line of
business witness a robust growth during
the
year we remain optimistic that the
industry will continue to grow given the
favorable macros regulatory changes low
penetration and relatively positive
consumer
sentiments coming to Performance The
General insurance industry delivered a
year on-year gross direct premium income
growth of 12.8% for financial year 20 24
excluding clo and mass he growth stood
at
14.8% overall the combined ratio for the
industry was at 112. 2% for 9 months
Financial year 2024 as against 11 16.2%
for 9 month Financial year
2023 for motor the combin ratio was at
11 18.2% for 9 month Financial year
20124 as against
121.9 for 9 month Financial year 2023
in our last earning calls we had
mentioned Improvement in the industry
combined ratio for motor for H1
Financial year 2024 by fin by 400 basis
points to 11
19.4% from 123.5 per for H1 Financial
year 2023 there has been a further
Improvement of 300 basis points for
quarter 3 only in the combined ratio of
a motor at 11
15.9% as against 11 18.9% during the
same period last year the motor combin
ratio for private players in Q3
Financial year 2024 was at
11.7% versus 11.8% for the same period
last year this Improvement indicates a
semblance of discipline coming back to
the
market as you may be aware new motor TP
hike has been announced for financial
year 2025 as yet we Will Be watchful of
how the industry response or to this in
coming days now I would like to touch
upon certain regulatory an announcements
on March 20th 2024 after a comprehensive
review of regulatory framework The
Authority notified a number of principal
based prescriptions the new regulations
include re notification of all tariff
notified by the Earth tariff advisory
committee which continued to be enforced
since December 2006 with the den
notification of the existing tariff the
company is at the Liberty to design all
the general insurance products in line
with its own underwriting policy
this would facilitate insurers to
respond faster to the Emerging Market
requirements and to design Innovative
products to cater to customers need it
may be mentioned that the pricing of
motor TP line of business continues to
be under the Tariff
regime rural social sector and motor
third party obligation prescribes a
minimum insurance business to be
undertaken by the insurers the
compliance and measurement of these
statutory obligations has been revised
in order to enhance the Insurance
penetration Lia sugam Insurance
electronic marketpl resolutions allow
for establishment of a digital public
infrastructure Insurance electronic
marketplace with this The Authority has
set out a vision of democratizing
insurance to achieve the goal of
insurance for all by
2047 we believe the regulatory
developments are favorable for the
industry I would like to further iterate
as a company we will as a company we
will continue to leverage the benefits
of being a diversified multi-product and
multi-distribution organization as we
capitalize on the existing and emerging
business opportunities in the
sector now I will speak about the
business impact for us in quarter 4 and
financial year
2024 The View by 22% during quarter 4
Financial year 2024 excluding a oneoff
transaction in the motor segment last
year growth was 15 8% which was higher
than the industry growth of
99.5% for
99.5% for financial year 2024 the
company grew by 17.8% as again the
industry growth of
12.8% excluding the oneof transaction
last year growth for financial year 2024
was
16.4% let me now touch upon our
performance in ke business segments
during the quarter and financial year
2024 in the commercial business segment
we continue to consolidate our Market
position by leveraging our unique
distribution Network enhanced by value
added Services student risk underwriting
and highly rated reinsurer Capac
capacities during quarter 4 2024 we view
at 11.3% as against an industry growth
of
11% so financially year 2024 we grew at
14.7% which was higher than the industry
growth of
10% further during the year we acov
market shares across segments such as
fire Marine cargo engineering and
liability as we speak we are at an
industry leading position in Marine
cargo and liability line of business
while being the second largest in Fire
and Engineering line of
business last year we experienced
significant rate hardening in the
reinsurance terms in line with global
Trends however as anticipated the recent
April 1 renewals have largely been
benign motor continues to be the largest
contributor to our product mix over the
year we have developed strong
capabilities across distribution
underwriting claims servicing and aial
practices given our presence across all
three Subs segments of Private Car two-
wheer and CV we would continue to
balance our portfolio next depending on
the market opportunities as we saw some
discipline return to the market we
scaled up our position in a calibrated
Manner and consequently ended the year
as an industry leader
the growth for us during the quarter was
27.3% excluding the oneof transaction
last year the growth for quarter 4 2024
was 13.4% as against the industry growth
of
99.6% for financial year 2024 we view at
12.3% excluding the oneof transaction
last year the annual growth was 8.9%
against the industry growth of
12.9% the growth in motor segment was
AED by strong growth in New Private Car
segment is GRE at 23% for quarter for
2024 and 28% for financial year 2024
which was higher than CM volume growth
of 12% and 8.4% respectively a new to
wheer growth was 11% for quarter 4 and
133% for financial year
2024 while the CM volume growth was
24.9% and 12.3%
respectively as real demand picks up we
expect to see the trend continue for two
wheelers in the new CV segment We DEW by
2.1% in quarter for 2024 and 1.9% in
financial year 2024 while the CM volume
growth was. 1% and 14.4%
respectively for financial year 2024 our
mix of Private Car two wheeler and
Commercial Vehicle stands at 31.4%
26.8% and 21.9% respectively
we also continue to build efficiency in
motor claims in quarter 4 2024 we were
able to service 70% of our agency and
direct claims through preferred partner
Network up from 54% in quarter for
2023 for the next year we expect mid
single digit growth in Private Car Sales
while the two- wheeler segment is
expected to deliver 8 to 10% growth CV
sales are expected to grow in double
digits in line with the previous year on
account of demand from infras
the health the health segment continued
to be the fastest growing segment for
the industry we grew faster than the
industry both in quarter 4 and financial
year 2024 registering a growth of 29%
for the quarter and full
year the group health employer employee
segment we grew at 31.7% in quarter 4
2024 and 30.3% in financial year 20124
the change in the underlying industry
pricing sentiments resulted in customer
moving towards ERS with Superior
servicing
capabilities our retail Sal business
grew by 21.8% in quarter 4 2024 against
the industry growth of
19.9% for financial year 2024 our retail
growth view retail business view at 20%
as against and the industry growth at
19.1% we would continue to invest in
this segment in terms of human
technology human uh human capital
technology and knowledge Capital to
further imp a market share our current
retail agency manager count stands at600
we will continue to strengthen our
growth L as we expect to achieve far
more than far more in this segment our
bank insurance and key relationship grew
at 16.7% for the quarter and 20.2% for
the financial year
2024 within this IC group distribution
view by
39.4% for quarter 4 Financial year 2024
and 22 2.5% for financial year 2024 we
will continue to deep mine our existing
Relationships by creating new value
streams and at the same time focus on
acquiring new relationship during the
year we added over 80 Banker
Partnerships in the last call we spoke
about a vision of one Al one team under
this one of our initiatives that we had
outlined in our one is our one is one
digital strategy through this we aim to
consolidate our customer facing digital
asset of I take care website and
alliances along with our distribution
facing front end this will allow us to
exploit the synergies across all our
platforms which will result in benefits
to the
company our onetop solution for all
insurance and wellness needs the IL take
care app has surpassed 9.3 million user
downloads till date we continue our
growth momentum with 8 million user
downloads for the quarter in the same
year the source premium over 1.13
billion and a premium of 3.68 billion
for financial year 2024 registering a 3X
increase on a YY
basis our overall customer facing
digital business grew at 29.5% in
quarter 4 and 39% in financial year 2024
and constitute 6.8% and 6% respectively
of our overall business last week we
announced a strategic tie up with policy
Bazar our TI is aimed at Ling leveraging
the strength of the two institutions to
create a superior customer value
proposition after transitioning to Cloud
we have continued to make significant
Investments on modernization of our
technology
platform along with this our Core
Business and Technology transformation
project project Oran is also underway
project toan will entail three pivotal
pillars of reimagining processes with a
digital first approach modernizing
technology by shifting away from Legacy
systems and enhancing stakeholder
experience to Superior enhanced
engagement models we are excited to
share that we have kickstarted the
transformation Journey with some of our
preferred line of businesses and are
witnessing the initiatives shaping up
nicely we firmly believe project to will
be a key enabler on our vision of one
Isis one team as the Empire on the new
Financial Year we will focus on
leveraging our multi-product
multi-distribution strategy through
effective use of data digital
advancements and launching new products
will maintain focus on scaling up for
profit pool while continuing to grow as
one Al one team now I would request
gopal to take you through the financial
numbers for the year for the Recently
concluded quarter and the year thanks s
and uh good evening to each one of you I
will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the
recently concluded quarter and financial
years
we have uploaded the results
presentation on our website you can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers during the quarter
IC Bank acquired additional Equity
shares of the company consequently the
shareholding of the bank in the company
has increased to more than 50% and the
company has become a subsidiary of the
bank brage direct premium income of the
company was at rupes 27.76 billion in fi
24 as against R 210.25 billion in f23 a
growth of 17.8%
which was higher than the industry
growth of
12.8% excluding crop and Mass health the
gdpi growth of the company was at
17.1% which was higher than the industry
growth of 14.8% in
f24 GDP of the company was at rupes
60.73 billion in quarter 4 fi 24 as
against R 49.77 billion in quarter 4
fi23 a growth of
22% this growth was higher than the
industry growth of
99.5% excluding crop and mass sales gdpi
growth was
22% which was again higher than the
industry growth of 13.88% in quarter 4
f24 our gdpi growth during f24 was
primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments the overall gdpi
growth of our Property and Casualty
segment grew by 14.7% at rupes 68.5 1
billion in f24 as against R 59.73
billion in fi23 on the retail side of
the business GDP of the motor segment
was at rupes 96.34%
85.8 billion f23 registering a growth of
12.3% the advanced premium was at rupes
33.3 billion at March 31 2024 as the g r
33.4 billion as at December 31 2023 GDP
of the health segment was at R 61.71
billion in f24 as against rupes
47.825445
128 411 as on March 31 2024 up from
12588 as on December 31 2023 during the
year we witnessed catastrophic events
namely Cyclone Vier jooy North Indian
floods and Cyclone Mong resultantly
combined ratio was 103.3 per for the
full year fi 24 as against 10 14.5% for
fi23 excluding the impact of these cat
losses of rupes 1.37 billion for the
full year the combin would have been at
1 10
12.5% for the quarter combined ratio was
10.2% in quarter 4 f24 as gained 10
14.2% in quarter 4 of fi23 our
investment assets Rose to rupes 48907
billion as at March 31 2024 up from
rupes 4686 7 billion as at December 31
2023 our investment leverage net of
borrowing was 4.09 times as at March 31
2024 as again changed 4.11 times as at
December 31 2023 investment income was
at
35.262781
this year as against R 8.17 billion in
Q4 of last year our capital gains net of
impairment and investment assets stood
at rupes 5.51 billion in FY 24 as
compared toes 4 53 billion in
fi23 capital gains net of empowerment
and investment assets stood at R 1.56
billion in quarter 4 fi 24 as compared
to rupes 1.59 billion in quarter 4 fi23
our profit before tax grew by 21% at R
2.55 billion in f24 as against R 21.13
billion in fi23 whereas profit before
tax grew by 21.9% at R 6.98 billion in
Q4 f524 as against 5.7 3 billion in Q4
fi23 consequently profit after tax grew
by 11% Ates 19.19 billion in f24 as
against rupes
17.29% in fi 24 profit after tax grew by
18.9% at rupes 5.2 billion in Q4 fi 24
fromes 4.37 billion in Q4 fi23 the board
of directors has proposed a final
dividend of R 6 per share for f24 this
payment is however subject to approval
of shareholders in the ensuing annual
general meeting of the company the
overall dividend for fi 24 including the
proposed final dividend is rupes 11 per
share last year the overall dividend was
rupes 10 per share return on average
Equity was 17.2% in fi 24 as against
17.7% in fi23 return on average equity
for the quarter for fi 24 was 17.8% as
against 17.2% in quarter 4 FY 23
solvency ratio was at 2.62 times at
March 31 2024 as against 2.57 times as
at December 31 2023 continued to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times as I conclude I
would like to reiterate that we continue
to stay focused on driving profitable
growth sustainable value creation and
safeguarding interest of policy holders
at all times we would uh we would like
to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we'll be to take any
questions uh at this point Thank
you thank you very much we will now
begin the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their touchone
telephone if you wish to withdraw
yourself from the question queue you may
press star and
two participants are requested to please
use handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will now wait
for a moment while the question Q
assembles
the first question comes from the line
of Shrea Shivani from clsa please go
ahead thank you and um congratulations
on a good set of numbers I have three
questions uh so first is on the overall
growth Outlook so a health book for us
has done quite well since past two years
since F22 the growth has been north of
25 30 40% right uh so so um expecting
some moderation and growth going ahead
what would be the key drivers for growth
in fi
2526 uh which segments would be driving
majority of the growth and how much
higher than industry growth can we
deliver in the years to come given that
motor segment is still the the combin
ratio is still though there has been an
improvement and discipline has come in
but it's still quite a high combined
ratio for us to for one to expect us to
grow very fast in the motor segment so
that's my first question on ke grow
drivers and how much faster than
industry can we grow in fi 2526 uh
second is on the motor TP segment uh
looking at the reserve triangles
reserving triangle for the motor segment
PP segment specifically so there has
been a much higher Reserve release in
accident year 18 1920 I mean the trend
looks much better than the previous
prior year Trend so how should we read
this data does this also significantly
add to your fi 24 loss ra show
Improvement on YY basis apart from more
new cars being sold um so that's that's
my second question and thir on the third
question is on the combined ratio we've
done quite well on the combined ratio
side um already at for the fourth
quarter that has G gone by much better
uh numbers over there so um going ahead
what is our guidance on combined ratio
and one question that i' also asked at
the an meet about uh considering uh
natural calamities as business as usual
going ahead does that change and combin
ratio guidance in any these are my three
questions thank
you so I go the other one I'll tell you
what is our view yeah so I think if you
look at on the first one sh I think uh
if you look at it from an overall Market
perspective uh I think as we have always
been saying we have been we have always
been looking at this business in the
context of being a multiproduct
multi-distribution setup and therefore
to that extent different segment of
businesses
uh presents opportunities for growth
maybe at different points of time and
hence to that extent is where I think we
have been able to kind of put in place a
model in place by which we are able to
leverage the growth potential uh so and
it is in that context when you look at
the overall year gone by I think we have
been able to have an outperformance
relative to the market growth and if you
look at in terms of how we are heading
into the next year I think there's a lot
of positive momentum that we see from
from an overall Market perspective as as
well one of course this flew of
regulatory reforms that we spoke as a
part of the introductory uh remarks I
think that augur well both from a market
standpoint and even from the opportunity
that it gives for Isis lomard I think
it's very very positive second I think
if you look at the thrust that the
government is putting on in terms of in
general looking at significant thrust of
infrastructure development that
obviously presents a lot more
opportunities on multiple segments of
businesses whether you look at it in the
commercial line space uh maybe for
example thrust on engineering projects
to begin with obviously to that extent
it kind of AIDS in logistics uh
transportation to again look at uh
growth profitably and more importantly
it is also expected to lead to let's say
higher number of uh jobs and therefore
to that extent it like as I said kind of
Aur very well uh in terms of the
opportunity that one sees specific to
your point on health I think as we
always said even in the past I think uh
the kind of opportunity that one sees in
the market if you look at few years back
the market was significantly stressed in
terms of the loss experience or and more
importantly whether you look at it from
a combined issue standpoint given that
some of the players are already kind of
looking at uh reversing some element of
pricing within Group Health and
particularly on the employer employee
side it obviously kind of aers well and
that's the reason why you see us uh
continuing to grow disproportionately
relative to the market and even as we
head into
fi25 We Believe health for for the
industry as well will continue to be by
far the one of the fastest growing
segments and within that even for IC
Lombard we see an opportunity on health
both in the groups Health as well as in
the retail Health segments uh so that's
whe whether the growth will be
continuing to be at 25 will it slightly
get moderated I think we will obviously
wait for things to evolve but honestly
as you have said even in the past I
don't think uh from a market perspective
we will continue to see prolonged
periods of 25 to 30% growth from an
industry standpoint so I think that's
something that we will obviously watch
for the second question on yours in
terms of the motor third party reserving
triangle I think uh it's good that the
market is starting to look at the
triangle disclosures from an overall
Market perspective I think that again
aers well because then every company is
being kind of proed to appropriate level
of scrutiny from a market perspective
and H to that extent it again aers well
from our overall Market discipline uh in
terms of uh uh the some of the let's say
the releases that you spoke about I
think if you ask us the way I would kind
of respond to it is whether have we is
there any change in the approach of our
reserving philosophy the approach is not
changed and in line with what we have
been speaking even in the earlier
quarters I think the way to look at on
the third party book as you rightly
mentioned is is more more on an annual
basis and in fact if you recollect uh
even last time in the quarters earnings
call we did speak about a range within
which we see the loss experience play
out for motor as a category and just to
kind of refresh that we had said motor
own damage loss experience is something
that we see in the range of 60 to 65%
and motor third party as a segment we
had said we would be kind of operating
at a range between 65 to 7% and both of
that Blended is where we had said motor
as a category would run in that range of
64 6 % and if you look at the F year
numbers both on motor own damage as well
as on motor third party I think broadly
the outcome of the book that we have
been able to underwrite has been within
that range that I just kind of uh
refreshed having said that one of the
key deliverables that we would obviously
watch for which also put which we put as
a part of the uh introductory remarks is
on motor third party pricing now as she
speak statement of fact is we have not
seen a price change so we will watch for
development in that pH and therefore to
that EXT the risk selection will
continue to be driven by some of the
factors that we see as we speak in terms
of no price increase thus far so we will
be guided more by that in terms of how
we see the opportunity the range of loss
experiences is a function of what I kind
of mentioned your last point on combined
ratio I think uh sh clearly I mean the
qu numbers on the combin ratio which
leads at
102.2 and they about where does it play
the overall commentary in terms of what
we have spoken ta events available
sectoral reform which are being
initiated by the
regulator uh we see a play and we do see
that we can have a you know over 50
basis Improvement further to what we had
said we will achieve as a team by
quarter four of next year U but uh again
we will keep revisiting and absolutely
will keep communicating but we do see
green shoots and that kind of an
improvement can come in overall for us
as an entity
so so what you're saying basically by
fi25 we were targeting 102 that can be
uh 50 books uh lower at 101.5 unless
there is some other and what about the
catastrophe events are we are we still
watching it or have we come to a
conclusion on how we should be dealing
with yes uh so clearly I think gopal
also in the past has been mentioning
that the frequency of catastrophic event
on the annual basis uh has got increased
and do we factor that when we speak
about it yes there is a level of
factoring but like a last year was an
exceptional one which was more than the
factory and that's why we keep stting in
terms of what would have happened if
those Cat event would not have been in
terms of quantum to that extent uh see
we in the business of writing risk at a
fundamental level do we watch do we
Factor all of that is part of the
process but the extend the extend the
event is something which we all await uh
we will keep you updated on that part
but there's some element which obviously
is big deal when we see that we are
overall expecting an improvement of 50
basis
points okay so so thank thank you this
is useful thank you thank
you ladies and gentlemen we request you
to please restrict your questions to two
questions per
participant we have the next question
from the line of sankit Goda from
Avengers spark please go ahead uh yeah
thank you thank you for the opportunity
I have two key questions uh one one
question is with the with respect to the
regulation um just just my my
understanding of that new obligation
Norms on motor TP seems to be more
stringent than it was in the previous
regime so so just wanted to understand
whether whether we would be confident to
fulfill the obligation of motor TP in
the new Norms uh is is the point we
wanted to I mean just wanted to
understand and and how you will achieve
it that's that's one question and and
second question which I want to
understand is that you have about one L
um but but if you want to quantify the
number uh due to one L what are the
synergies you are expecting to see
either in the form of gwp growth because
because you now aligning agents across
the business segment or distribution
across the segments so so so you expect
the synergies and and if mean quantify
the number in terms of gwp additional
gwp or or maybe an additional
Improvement in the expense ratio because
of these synergies and and lastly on
data keeping uh uh if you can share
retail and Group Health loss ratio and
and gopal to last Point sorry that that
if the no TP price high do in come are
you still confident that
65% okay so I'll take the first two and
then the other one other the data that
you seing in the last question gopal
will come in and give it to you uh in
terms of the new TP regulations that
have come in see I mean the insurance
The Authority has clearly said that
they're looking for insurance for all by
2047 and for that some initiation has to
be done uh the conol of how this will uh
emerge for all of us has still to emerge
uh it's kind of work in progress but
that being said see we are multi-line
multiproduct well distributed franchise
with so much of retail I mean we with do
as an entity humongus so we are present
we would definitely back Tes to achieve
uh uh the objectives that are set by the
regulator but we would be speculating
beyond the point as to where we where we
will be placed we have complete Clarity
in terms of what's expected from us so
that's Point number one under one one uh
one team that we've been talking about
and really emphasizing uh quantification
fundamentally comes with the qu results
that you will see us announcing and we
would refrain from attaching uh you know
finite value because the overall
performance is subject to scrutiny which
we keep announcing to all of you and uh
uh are we excited in terms of seeing
both Top Line and cost getting you know
control in a relatively better manner
the answer is yes definitely and we do
believe coming quarters will AC but we
will not be you know cing it out and
calling that this has happened because
of this overall the efficiency of
company will be you know will be
reflected in how we perform as an entity
and there are multiple other aspects
that come you know we may have some
genuine savings we may choose to
reinvest also that so we would not like
to you know dwell on this on those
aspects you give a 50 basis point better
guidance than than what it was last year
so so is it because of this one what you
are trying
to again what I what I again you know
you know rush into I get from where your
excitement is coming from this would be
one of the Contours we always maintained
that the industry sentiments also has to
move in the positive direction they
always maintained the fact that they
would be an output of where the overall
industry growth is and how our own
placement is so is this an element that
comes in and binds us together as an
organization 110% answer is yes uh but
to quantify this keep this from this
output this much has come because of one
one team will not
be will not be fair with all I'm say so
there are multiple things that go in
back for the other two questions that
you have goal to re to you yeah so so
sank on the health loss numbers uh again
I'll give you Q4 numbers first and then
I'll give you the F year numbers Q4 on
the uh ghi which is employer employee
segment this is for quarter four of last
year which is f23 that number is at
93.2%
that number for quarter four of this
year is at
88.1% uh and on a full year basis for
the same segment I think the range that
we have spoken about is to operate in
the range of 94 95% if you look at fi23
the overall loss ratio on the ghi side
was
95.2% and this year we are at about
93.7% on retail Health again just to
kind of refresh uh what we have talked
about even in the past several quarters
is we're comfortable operating in the
loss R show range which is between 65 to
70% in that context when you look at the
quarter 4 fi23 numbers retail which is
on the indemnity side that loss ratio
was about
61% that number for quarter four of this
year is at
64.6% and on a full year basis last year
number was
64.1 and the current year number is at
about
65.4 uh so that's in in response to your
second point on the health loss numbers
the last question of yours in in terms
of uh whether the range that I spoke
about of 65 to 70% in the context of
motor third party uh so again I think
that's the range that we have kind of
largely operated at I think the only
factor that I would say is uh in line
with again what we've been speaking even
in the past few quarters as in to say
that what we are seeing on ground is
also maybe an increased preference of
the courts to start giving compensation
in favor of uh the victims of the
insurance and therefore so that's a
trend that we will obviously
observe the other factor which would
again which we have which we have again
spoken of which should be directionally
positive is also this whole six months
law of limitation in terms of how that
gets played out uh last year of course
we did see some developments and finally
as we have been saying the matter is
presently at the Supreme Court once the
verdict comes out I think we will again
have to see in terms of how that play
get played out on ground so hence there
are again balancing forces in terms of
ones that could possibly see or reflect
an increase in the loss experience
that's really then it's up to us in
terms of what kind of risk selection do
we do and the second is more a positive
benefit at least for I Lumbard from an
over overall R activeness standpoint and
then to that extent that that should
kind of Aid Us in terms of maintaining
the L is range of 65 to 70% so there are
lot of moving parts now at this point of
time I think we would want to kind of
stick with uh the 65 to 70% range and of
course we will see some of these factors
in terms of how that get paid out
through the
year perfect thanks thanks for your
responses thank you thanks than you
thank
you thank
you the next question is from the line
of NES from invest Tech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity uh
first question is on IFRS so any uh any
update what are the timelines for
expected implementation of iars and what
would be the impact on
sheet so NES I think again in line with
what I had mentioned even in the last
earnings call I think we had said that
uh we are pretty much uh progressing
well in terms of doing the impact
assessment making sure that we get
ourselves ready for the implementation
which is effective from fi 25 26
Financial year uh and even last quarter
we did say that we will come back in
maybe couple of quarters time frame so
honestly internally while we are doing
all of those and also watching for uh
the developments in terms of all the
necessary guidelines and standards
getting issued in the context of the
IFRS transition so therefore at this
point of time too early to call out but
as I always maintained I think we have
clearly spoken about three or four key
uh areas or aspects which is where we
would likely to see the impact of
transition playout in the context of
high so that doesn't change um whether
it is in terms of acquisition cost
whether it is in terms of
discounting of reserves whether it is in
terms of Mark to Market on the
investment book and maybe for few set of
companies which have kind of issued uh
let's say stock units or stock options
so there will be an element of cost
through the earnings so those are three
or four key areas where one would see an
impact of the transition playout
specifically to call out I think we will
come back and obviously keep all of you
updated in terms of uh where we are on
the IFR
establish sure sure and secondly in
terms of solv ratio we are operating at
significantly higher number versus
theary threshold and our Roes have also
now improved to 17 to 18% uh so do we
think of better utilization of capital
going
forward no of course that's obviously
something that we kind of uh uh is
something that we always look for uh I
think one of the factors that you see
which also led to let's say Improvement
in solvency and of course Improvement in
earnings over the last few years has
been our approach to as what sanj was
also been talking about is to sustain
profitable growth as a theme and hence
in let's say relative to the market I
think we have been slightly slowing
going slow on some of the segments and
therefore to that extent we have not
been able to completely utilize the
solvency Capital what we are seeing is
what we kind of put out as a part of the
introductory remark which is to say that
on ground we are seeing semblance coming
back in uh some of the segments where we
have we have been a bit cautious and
therefore to that extent as we see let's
say incremental growth play out in L in
line with our approach to continue to
grow as well as kind of remain
profitable obviously there will be
consumption of capital that one would
see uh in terms of uh the way forward uh
and secondly I think the approach of the
philosophy that isos has always worked
with is to be slightly more prudent in
terms of the level of solvency that we
want to maintain given the fact that the
Indian market still continues to operate
on a solvency one regime while again uh
thanks to the regulator they have been
significantly working on getting the
market again transition to a risk-based
capital regime obviously we will get to
know more in terms of the firm date of
implementation in terms of the
transition uh so hence that that that's
something again that we will see in
terms of how does that result into in so
far as the consumption of capital is
concerned so while we do see growth
opportunities and hence to that extent
we believe we will continue to use the
capital uh
judiciously so and lastly on the
provision for dimin in value of
investment of around 68 crores what is
the reason for that and then we disclose
the capital gain number that is
excluding this rejoin the que for
followup
questions okay sir thank
you the next question is from the line
of PR Jen from moil oswal please go
ahead uh yeah hi good evening uh so
firstly just a clarification when you
say 101.5 as a guidance that is for the
exit rate of 24 of next year or it's for
the uh full year uh secondly if I you
know like just uh just going back to one
of the uh previous questions on the
motor TP business on your you know the
obligation if the share of CV goes up do
you still uh believe that that you know
65 to 70% guidance can be maintained um
and and with that you know gopal time
and again you know we've seen Q4 loss
ratios improve sequentially increase
sequentially for motp is it just because
of the adverse judgments that come in Q4
or what is it that really gives that
kind of a loss ratio uptrend in every
fourth quarter uh yeah I think those
would be my two questions yeah yeah
maybe I'll take the the uh uh TP loss
isue part first uh I think Whenever
there is let's say
possible uh reduction in the TP loss
ratios the questions get asked the other
way around so and therefore to that
extent uh I think as I think I have
always kind of maintained that this is a
book which is much more longtail in
terms of loss development and therefore
to that extent given the nature of the
business you will always see cyclicality
SL fluctuations in the loss experience
of the book in terms of its outcome so
therefore which is why I keep harping on
looking at the numbers I over longer
term but definitely not between quarters
look at it more on an annual basis um
and as I keep saying again there are
various factors that influences uh let's
say the loss experience of the book I
think uh so hence to that extent you
will get to see fluctuations in the TP
loss ratios across Quarters on a full
year basis is what I spoke about in
terms of trying to maintain us operating
at a segment uh I mean segment loss
ratio in that range of 65 to 70% uh now
coming back to your first second part of
the question in terms of link to motor
third party is the obligation now
obviously the the obligation is
something that is applicable to Industry
at large and therefore as as a company I
mean uh we have to make sure that we
kind of meet those uh obligations and
I'm sure we will have in place a plan by
virtue of which we are able to meet uh
the regulatory expectations I think the
the thought process in terms of where
the regulator is coming out with the
need to bring about this change is again
very very positive because the whole
thought process is to try and make sure
that the industry kind of comes under
the Ambit of insurance and to that
extent that's very very positive and if
you're able to do as as an industry if
you're able to work collectively and
maybe bring the larger set of let's say
uninsured vehicles within the Ambit of
insurance that to my mind is a great
positive and hence to that extent uh I
think we would obviously work and make
sure that we able to meet those uh
obligations of the third party side uh
the first part on the combined ratio uh
uh part I think obviously yes I think
dally the lens that we have talked about
mes ises is that we have we have been
saying that directionally the uh
trajectory for us is to bring down the
combined over a period of time and
obviously this has to be looked at in
the context of how we see the market
environment operate act uh which is why
I think even as a part of of the
introductory remark we did point out to
say that the market is clearly showing
signs of at least from the reported
numbers on a 9 Monon BSIS There is
almost a 400 Business Point Improvement
in Combined uh from an overall Market
perspective and within that one of the
key segment which has been a larger
contributor of significant competitive
intensity has been motored that's again
a segment which has again not just on a
half yearly basis even if you look at
the quarter quarter three numbers for
the market that's again shown an
improvement of almost about 300 bases
point so which is why I think we kind of
put out to say that there seems to be
some kind of a semblance coming back and
that's also getting reflected in terms
of the growth numbers that many of these
players were exhibiting in terms of
competitive aggression clearly you can
see a lot many players are starting to
kind of pull back so that gives us
possibly some kind of a confidence uh in
terms of how do we look at achieving
that uh combined objective that we laid
out and H to that extent even in the
past I think what we have maintained is
what I mean if the market environment is
favorable there is no reason why we
would not be able to accelerate the
expectations of combine and that is
where we are that is why we stand and uh
and and in all finers we hope to kind of
ACH
achieve the thought process that we laid
out from a combined perspective it's for
it's for the full year right that's the
clarification as think stand and proba
we'll be in touch on this we believe the
exit would be overall the 50 B is less
there are serious plans of Investments
also we would uh Continue to update as
the quarters and F because as gopal said
these are early signs that makes us
optimistic and sees the visibility of
this but uh there are multiple things
that will unfold as of now in our mind
it will be probably exit by quarter 4 is
where we would see this and if it gets
further accelerated we'll come back and
uh connect with you all by end of
quarter one of this year great thank and
all the
best thank
you we have the next question from the
line of mukar Lada from NV wealth please
go
ahead U hi congratulations on a good set
of numbers so most of my questions have
been answered I wanted to understand uh
investment yields have improved uh again
uh this quarter and even if we exclude
um even if we exclude the capital gains
uh we're doing quite well so uh what is
the number that we should be sort of
looking at in this and uh what is the
duration how are we driving this
actually that that is one question on my
mind thank you sure
yeah so again mukar I think again I
would kind of respond this in the
context of I'm sure you guys know it far
better I think obviously Investments
have to be looked at in terms of it
return return profile over a period of
time uh and hence to that extent is how
what we keep saying is to look at Market
opportunities in terms of uh having a
blended mix of the right asset classes
between both fixed income and equity and
that's what we have been kind of looking
at over the period of time in terms of
of realizing the opportunities now
specifically to Anor point on what led
to let's say the increase in the uh
interest yield or let say the overall
return on the portfolio is it is in line
with the high higher interest rate
regime that we have seen and obviously
one leverages the opportunity and even
if you look at historical past in terms
of what kind of a mix of our overall
returns have been in terms of Interest
approvals to let's say capital gains
that mix has broadly been on the interr
side in the range of 75 to 80% and on
the capital gain side number that could
range between 15 to 20 20 20 25% around
that kind of a threshold so hence to
that extent is how we see the
opportunity play out and specifically if
you look at our yield to maturity uh on
the fix income side the yeld to maturity
currently stands at about
7.4% uh so hence and that's the that's
the opportunity that one was able to
seize in the market and uh now can we
sustain this obviously we will have to
wait and see how the interest rate cycle
play out uh there are clear expectations
that you will start seeing some kind of
a rate reduction cycle play through at
some point of time again we are
positioned well even to capitalize that
opportunity but what could happen at
those points is our ability to reinvest
those uh realized flows will obviously
get invested at a lower return on the uh
approval side but obviously we are well
positioned to capitalize the opportunity
from a capital gains standpoint and
therefore now to answer your point on
the overall range of returns that we can
operate with again if you look at fi23 I
think the overall return on the realized
book was roughly at about 7.5% this
number if you look at for fi 24 was
roughly at about 7.98 closer to 8% um
and the range I mean internally the
range that we kind of run with is to
kind of give a return profile between 7
to 7 and a half% and but over our last
now that we are almost 23rd 24th year of
operations I think the return profile
has been definitely better than that
particular range so that's a range that
we would be comfortable with uh and
hence that extent is where we would
would like to
operate thanks thanks very helpful thank
you thanks for
the thank
you ladies and gentlemen we will now
take the last question for today from
the line of Aditi josi from JP Morgan
please go
ahead uh yes sir thank you for my
question taking my question uh just one
followup question um which I wanted to
understand from you on the comp uh the
investment in inity in the channel uh so
for the uh fer 2025 what is the Outlook
as been of the investment in the channel
uh in terms of the intensity are you
going to increase further or just wait
for the Investments the last in the last
couple of years to Cy and then just some
guidance on that will be helpful so so
again if you look at I think what we put
out even as a part of the introductory
comment is I think just to kind of
refresh again I think we always looked
ourselves as a multi-distribution uh
company and therefore to that extent is
how we see opportunity play out across
different channels if you ask us would
we stay entrenched with each of these
channels the answer is clear yes I think
in so far as let's say as we see new
motor vehicle sales gaining momentum and
therefore to detction obviously we will
kind of Leverage on the access SL
Partnerships that we have been able to
create historically of working with OEM
slash more importantly the dealership
touch points and that's reason if you
look at across years the proportion of
dealership access that we have had out
of the total number of dealerships as a
country again just to kind of refresh
that number used to be between 50 to 55%
at the time when we did our listing
currently we have been able to reach
that number closer to in slightly upward
of 65% uh in terms of the total number
of leadership so that will continue to
be an important channel of distribution
agency which kind of encompasses between
motor
healthme has always been an area of
opportunity and that's a segment which
obviously we have been kind of expanding
a lot more and clearly we have seen
benefits of the Investments play out
whether you look at onme I think the
growth rates over the last several years
have been very positive even on let's
say I would say uh agency motor I think
that's a segment where we have talked
about trying to create a balanced mix
between dealership agency and let's say
our direct distribution so hence to that
extent obviously we will continue to
leverage on uh motage agency
specifically and in specific since we're
talking in the context of agency retail
health is always a positive opportunity
that one sees uh and that's the reason
why we put out that number of the
headcount that we have on our own health
agency managers which is currently at
about, 1600 and we would want to
continue to see expansion in that
particular space so you will obviously
see a lot more expansion initiatives
being undertaken in the context of
retail health and therefore to the
action that should logically translate
into an improved market share uh in that
particular segment while even this we
would have loved to have done better but
honestly we have not been able to
completely leverage the uh opportunity
that one sees but given the fact that we
have been able to uh strengthen our
leadership team as well I think one
would expect a lot more to happen in
terms of expanding distribution
launching new products and obviously
strengthening the technology
deliverables uh so that's so agency will
continue to be a very very important
channel of sourcing and sanjie in the
last earning calls did speak about one
is one digital uh Channel and therefore
that will again continue to be a very
very important channel of sourcing and
if you look at just from the current
year standpoint the overall contribution
of the digital opportunity that spans
across I take care website Alliance
Partners etc etc that contribution has
been almost in the range of almost 6 to
7% of the overall revenues and that's
again kind of compounding well in in
excess of almost about 20% year on year
so all in all I think uh it is going to
be a combination of all channels I think
there is going to be thrust of
Investments in each of them if you ask
me which channel will by far gain the
Maximum Traction obviously retail health
is an area where we would want to kind
of significantly leverage faster and
then of course we have the digital
opportunity that one sees and then we
will continue to leverage on the other
channels of and more importantly I just
I did miss one of them which is the bank
Partnerships I think again that will be
a very very important area of sourcing
and within that icsi group will be a
very very important contribution for us
and hence we would obviously want to
leverage on each of these channels of
distribution
thank you very much can I can I just
squeeze in one more can you please uh
share your outlook of the health pricing
both in the retail and the group that
would be helpful thank you outlook on
health uh pricing pricing the health
insurance pricing yeah in both the
retail segment that's Rel in the group I
think uh it's it's it's a function of
loss ratio and as you said we will
continue to be a prudent underwriter uh
in both the segments uh most of the
industry including us have taken a hike
on the retail Health side last year so
we would believe as things stand we
would like to operate in this range uh
and while we will obviously keep
revisiting in terms of frequency as well
as a loss ratio that comes along with it
but that's what I VI retail is group is
far more Dynamic and uh driven by
multiple you know factors uh in the
market uh is it holding up overall yes
there has been some bit of a discipline
that continues to exist and is that's
what stay then we would obviously stay
relevant if it does not work out for us
we would not hesitate to move away and
let go that business if it's not making
sense that Clarity we have and we always
m i again reiterate that uh profit pools
keep moving and accordingly we have to
be agile as an organization we will take
those calls uh uh because we want to to
the best of our effort want to ensure
that we deliver what the market is
expecting with us for a multi-line
multiproduct company like
us thank you very much thank thank you
thank
you I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri for
closing comments over to you sir thank
you so much for joining in it's an
auspicious day of ram Nai and proba some
of your holidays uh it's always a
pleasure uh interacting with all of you
but the opportunity as it stays the
momentum that we have developed we are
excited about the opportunity ahead uh
look forward to interacting with you in
time to come and all the best Take Care
thank you so
much thank you on behalf of ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited that concludes this conference
thank you all for joining us you may now
disconnect your lines